Maulik Shetty

ullet Edinburgh, United Kingdom ullet maulikshetty@gmail.com $oldsymbol{\mathscr{O}}$ maulikshetty ullet maulikshetty

About Me

My Interests are currently in machine learning, cyber security and web development. Currently working with machine learning algorithms and sentimental analysis tools for a research project. As a fourth year computer science student, I have strong background in web development, logical and critical thinking, and currently improving and working on cloud deployment and hosting full stack applications.

Education

Heriot-Watt University (HWU), Edinburgh, United Kingdom

Sept 2021 - Present

Bachelor of Science in (Hons) in Computer Science

- o Completed Year 1 to 3 in Dubai Transferred to HWU UK Campus for final year
- Currently doing a research project for predicting stock market trends using sentimental analysis (SA) on X (formerly Twitter) data

The Indian High School (IHS), Dubai, United Arab Emirates High School Diploma

Apr 2008 - Mar 2021

o Graduated High School in Business, Accounting, Economics and Computer Science

Experience

Lab Demonstrator — Teaching Assistant Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh

Sep 2024 - Present

- Lab Assistant for Data Communications and Networking Module
- Grading and assisting students with GNS3 and computer networking

Low Code Intern Sharaf DG - UAE Head Quarters

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

- Wrote documentation that clearly and concisely described the technical architecture of the application.
- Supported application development and resolved issues by collaborating with outsourced developers.
- Assisted in troubleshooting and brainstorming new application features planned ahead

$\mathbf{A}\mathbf{wards}$

TDRA / UAE Hackathon - Zayed University Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

- Designed and pitched a web application for startups and venture capitals providing company insights from startups to established businesses
- Received extraordinary participation certificate

$\begin{tabular}{ll} \bf Deputy\ Principal\ Award\ -\ Heriot-Watt\ University\ {\it Dubai},\ {\it United\ Arab\ Emirates} \\ \hline \it{rates} \end{tabular}$

 $Aug\ 2022$

o Received Deputy Principal Award for achieving an A in at least 6 modules for one year

Projects

Web Browser Based on C#

qithub 🗹

• Description: Designed and implemented a web browser using C#, with features like HTTP request handling, history management, favorites, and a simple GUI.

Barcode Scanner - Terminal Based

github 🗹

• Description: Using python libraries such as opency, zxing to detect barcodes in real time from the live camera feed and return the product details.

Weather Application - Web Based

github \square

 \circ Description: Using Django, a python web framework to display weather of the current location and countries all around the world.

Skills

Languages: Python, Java, C#

Technologies: Vim, GNU Nano, AWS, Jupyter, SQL, Git, Linux, .NET

Soft Skills: Tensorflow, Pytorch, Scikit-Learn, LaTeX